RAGHUL G

+(91) 7577948377 \diamond Chennai, TamilNadu, India

raghulgopal2002@gmail.com ♦ Raghul Gopal ♦ www.raghulg.com ♦ Raghul G

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer (AI and Cloud), Data Scientist, AI Research Scientist with 3+ Years of College Level Exp.

AWS Cloud Club Captain for India Region, one among the 10 candidates from India. Principle AI & Cloud Lead, Organizer of AWS Cloud Club at St. Joseph's Institute of Technology, delivering AWS impacts and efficiencies to students through Technology meetups, Hands-on-Session, and more

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Information Technology, St. Joseph's Institute of Technology

2020 - 2024

Relevant Coursework: Artificial Intelligence, Cloud Computing, Algorithms, DataStructures, Operating Systems, DataBase Management Systems

CGPA (Penultimate Year): 8.79/10.0

Higher Secondary, AV Meiyappan Mat. Hr. Sec. School

2019 - 2020

Relevant Coursework: Higher Secondary in Computer Science Degree with an aggregate 85.33%.

EXPERIENCE

Youtuber - Tech with Rahul G

March 2023 - Present

YouTube

Chennai, TamilNadu

- Content Creator, Technology Meetups, Gathering, Software Engineering Skills, AI Research, Cloud Practitioner Roles
- Serves as the Main Source for **AWS Cloud Club at St. Joseph's Institute of Technology**, where Technical Meet-ups with Experts, Events from the Club, Online classes, Hands-on-Session to AWS Services, and more.

Machine Learning Internship

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Stigmata Techno Solutions

Chennai, TamilNadu

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and launch a new AI-powered product, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue for the company.
- Streamlined data processing pipeline, reducing processing time by 30% and increasing the efficiency of the team's workflow.
- Devised and executed the AI strategy for the MSI project, with a 70% project contribution, resulting in a successful takeover by Stigmata Techno Solutions.
- Created 5 UML Design Diagrams for MSI modules, and took charge of SRS development, achieving seamless inter-module communication and reducing development time by 20%.
- Developed a comprehensive AWS False Key detection system utilizing Logistic Regression and Natural Language Toolkit LSTM models to achieve accuracy rates of 75% and prototype accuracy rates of up to 95%, improving security measures by flagging false keys with an accuracy rate of 91%.

Data Science Internship

Feb 2022 - May 2022

AP-3 Solutions

Chennai, TamilNadu

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate the object detection model into an end-to-end workflow, resulting in a significant reduction in manual effort and cost savings of **50K per year**.
- Automated the data pre-processing pipeline to handle a large number of satellite images and reduced processing time by 60%, enabling faster model iteration cycles.
- Enhanced the performance of the image detection algorithm by implementing a new methodology using Convolutional Neural Networks with RPN, resulting in a 40% increase in accuracy for identifying buildings and water bodies.

- Managed a team of 5 interns, overseeing their daily tasks and providing guidance on complex machine learning algorithms, resulting in a 20% decrease in error rates.
- Developed and executed a rigorous training program for the intern team, resulting in a 30% increase in coding efficiency and accuracy.

PROJECTS

Object Detection Model using Images in Amazon SageMaker.

April 2023 — Present

Link to the Project

- Multiscale model to detect 2 objects namely weeds, and insects present in the agricultural plant image. The dataset is taken from **inaturalist.org**.
- Used MXNet has a backend, and SageMaker GroundTruth to automate the labelling process. This made to reduce the cost and productivity issues of the model to 25% of the original.
- Finally, working on deeper insights about the model, and the project is almost 80% completed. Deployment stages, Visualization, and final accuracy is pending.
- Tech Stack Using: AWS Management Console, AWS SageMaker, AWS S3, AWS QuickSight, SageMaker Groundtruth, MxNet

3D Printing of Pharmaceuticals using Artificial Intelligence

Jul 2021 - Jan 2023

Link to the Project

- Built a prototype which is to automate the process of solid pharmaceutical production using **3D printing** Fused Deposition Model.
- In association with **Prof. Dr.Rajkumar Velu** from **IIT Jammu**, scaled up the resources needed for manufacturing, and automated the wholesome process. Achieved greater accuracy in all the modules ranging from 80% to 90%
- Tech Stacks Used: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn

False Crypto Currency Detection and Prediction

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Link to the Project

- Scaled to detect the 11 types of false Crypto key and validate the future volume in using **LSTM and Conjugated LSTM**.
- \bullet Final Accuracy calculated is 90% for LSTM. For Conjuagated LSTM, accuracy scaled up to 86% which is better than other models suggested.
- Tech Stacks Used: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-Learn

Automation of Fluoroscopic Imaging using Machine Learning

July 2022 - Sep 2022

Link to the Project

- In association with **Dr. Aishwarya** from **Andijan State Medical Institute**, **Uzbekistan**, examined 4 diseases from public and real-time datasets.
- Adaboost Regressor gave a 91% score, PCA decomposes with a score of 72% to pass the decomposed images to AdCNN.
- Accurate predictions up to 91% and AdCNN accuracy is 93% measured.
- Tech Stack Used: IBM Quantum, Qiskit, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn

Exploratory Data Analysis of OTT Platforms

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

Link to the Project

- This project covers 3 major OTT Platforms namely Amazon Prime Video, Netflix, and Hotstar.
- With the help of the ggplot2 function available in R, plotted various plots to analyze the graphs based on 3 major categories namely age, gender, and duration.
- Tech Stack Used: R, R Studio

SKILLS

Technical Skills Python, Java, C, R, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Frameworks Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Pytorch, Scikit-learn, AWS SageMaker

RDBMS MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQlite

Cloud Platform AWS Cloud Practitioner, AWS Machine Learning Specialty

Data Analytics Matplotlib, Numpy, Pandas, Plotly

Techathlon 2023 - Paper Presentation

- 1st Place in Paper Presentation for the Paper titled Automation of Fluoroscopic Imaging using Machine learning QTP for DICOM Image Transfer
- Grabbed **3000 INR** as a Cash Price for the best Research Paper.

Seimens Shift Hackathon 2022

- One of the top 10 Finalists among 500 teams from all over India.
- Grabbed 10,000 INR as an incentive for a notable project among the finalists.

KPMG Malta Hackathon

- One of the **Finalists** among 1500 teams where the business idea has been proposed for Online Shopping since the Covid pandemic peak.
- Grabbed 30\$ as incentives for the best 15 ideas among 500 shortlisted teams

TamilNadu Police Hackathon 2022

- Secured 4th Position in Tamil Nadu Police Hackathon 2022 with my teammate.
- Received 3000 INR for the best project discussion and idea generation.

Rapyd Hackathon 2022

- Secured one among the top 100 teams for best idea simulation, and innovative prototype discussion.
- Received **30** \$ as an incentives for best idea proposal.

KPIT Sparkle 2022

• Secured one among the top 100 teams from 500 teams for the Sustainable development phase of Energy in the Hackathon.

Innopreneurs Ideathon

- Shortlisted among 10,000 participants for the best startup idea.
- Secured 10,000 INR goodies for the best startup idea.

CONFERENCES & PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Rajkumar, V, Karthi, M., Raghul, G (2023). Intelligent Automation of Pharmaceuticals Production using 3D Printing. Flexible Services and Manufacturing Journal (Review). Retrieved 2023.
- 2. Karthi, M., Raghul, G. (2023). False Crypto Currency Detection and Analysis using LSTM and Conjugated LSTM. International Conference on Futuristic Digital Technologies for Sustainable Development ICFDTSD. Retrieved 2023.
- 3. Karthi, M. Raghul, G. (2023). Automation of Fluoroscopic Imaging through AI. Advanced Biotechnology and Pharmacy. Retrieved 2023.
- 4. Karthi, M., Raghul, G., Priscilla, R. (2023). AdCNN-QT Ensemble Advanced Method for Diagnosing Medical Images and Quantum Teleportation for DICOM Image Transfer. Physics in Medicines and Biology (Review). Retrieved 2023.
- 5. Raghul, G. (2023). *U-NET and RCNN Ensembled Satellite Object Detection and Segmentation*. IEEE Explore. Retrieved from https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10073720
- 6. Karthi, M., Raghul, G., Priscilla, R. (2022). Automation of Fluoroscopic Imaging through AI QTP for Secured DICOM Image Transfer. International Conference for Recent Advances in Biotechnology and Environmental Science 2022. Retrieved 2023.
- 7. Raghul, G. (2022). Mask Segmentation and Object Detection in Satellite Imagery. International Conference on Emerging Trends, Innovation in Science, Engineering, and Education. Retrieved 2022.